Alexander Chermenin

Saint Petersburg, Russia <u>alex@chermenin.ru</u> <u>http://chermenin.ru</u>

I began programming when I was about 8 years old. Started small - wrote my first programs using long-forgotten language G-BASIC, later QuickBasic, and then Delphi with all its charms of visual programming. Year by year, time passed, technologies has changed (there was time when I wrote on C++, C#, Ruby, Scala, Haskell, and recently more and more PHP and even more Java), and this isn't all. I worked in "Prognoz" (http://prognoz.com), "Pro IT" (http://proitr.ru) and "DartIT" (http://dartit.ru).

Technical Skills

Likes:

c#, java, php, javascript, scala, spring, hibernate, multithreading, servlets, json, rest, oracle, mongodb, mssql, mysql, hadoop, apache-spark, hive, bigdata

Experience

Principal Software Developer - Sberbank-Technology

July 2015 - Current

java, spring, xslt, xml, xpression, xforms, tomcat, websphere, git, hadoop, apache-spark, scala, hive, bigdata

- web forms development using IBM Forms
- development of web services using Java with (and without) Spring
- big data processing using Java and Scala with Hadoop, Spark and Hive

Middle Java Developer - DartlT

March 2015 - June 2015

java, angularjs, spring, aop, oracle, weblogic, maven, intellij-idea, git, mercurial, jpa, hibernate, rest, servlets, mongodb

- · development of web interfaces using AngularJS
- · development of web services using Java with (and without) Spring and Hibernate
- deployment and support Apache Tomcat
- · support for database Oracle

Java Developer - Pro IT

September 2014 – March 2015

java, angularjs, spring, aop, oracle, weblogic, maven, intellij-idea, git, mercurial, jpa, hibernate, rest, servlets, mongodb

- development of web interfaces using AngularJS
- development of web services using Java EE with Spring and Hibernate
- · deployment and support Oracle WebLogic
- support for database Oracle

PHP / Java Developer - JSC Prognoz

July 2013 - September 2014

php, java, gwt, javascript, apache, tomcat, servlets, rest, objective-c, oracle, mssql, websphere, angularjs, maven, intellij-idea, git, mercurial, svn, jpa, spring, hibernate

- · web application development using Java and GWT
- development of web interfaces using AngularJS
- development of web services using Java EE with Spring and Hibernate
- · development of web applications using PHP
- deployment and support Apache HTTP Server, Apache Tomcat
- deployment and support GlassFish Server
- deployment and support Oracle WebLogic
- support for database Oracle

Junior PHP / Java Developer - JSC Prognoz

June 2010 - July 2012

php, java, gwt, javascript, apache, tomcat, servlets, rest, objective-c, oracle, mssql, websphere

- development of information-analytical systems and decision support systems using its own analytical complex Prognoz Platform and through third-party programming systems (Microsoft Visual Studio, XCode)
- development of monitoring services using Microsoft Visual Studio (C#)
- · development of web interfaces using ASP.NET technology
- development of mobile applications for iPad using XCode (Objective-C)
- deployment and support of database Microsoft SQL Server 2008 R2, Oracle 11g
- · installation and configuration of OS Red Hat, AIX
- deployment of IBM WebSphere and IBM InfoSphere MDM for PIM

Education

Engineer at specialty information system and technologies – Perm State Agricultural Academy 2008 – 2015 pascal, freepascal, delphi, java, php, mssql, active-directory, windows, windows-server-2008, autocad, c++, networking, security, gis, electronics

Projects & Interests

Sija Framework - http://chermenin.github.io/sija/

php, json, activerecord, rest

Sija is an open source software implementation of some guidelines and small framework written in PHP to help quickly and easily create a simple REST-services and web applications.

Author and developer

Imtec Battery Mark - http://chermenin.ru/bmark/

delphi, acpi, wmi

Imtec Battery Mark is a powerful software solution that tests the laptop battery and helps you determine whether it needs to be replaced or not.

Author and developer

GitHub - Sija Framework - https://github.com/chermenin/sija

July 2014 - August 2015

php, json, activerecord, rest

Sija is an open source software implementation of some guidelines and small framework written in PHP to help quickly and easily create a simple REST-services and web applications using JSON API.

Author and developer

Bitbucket - FreelanceHunt Messenger - https://bitbucket.org/chermenin/flh-November 2014 - December 2014 messenger

java, javafx, multithreading, dto, web-services

Client for FreelanceHunt web site using API.

Author and developer

Bitbucket - Simple Java XML Server - https://bitbucket.org/chermenin/xml November 2014 - February 2015 server

java, groovy, xml, jetty

This is implementation of a simple server for education.

Author and developer

Battery Mark for OS X - https://itunes.apple.com/ru/app/battery-mark/id1022826698

objective-c, core-plot, osx, xcode

Battery mark is a great tool that allows you to evaluate overall status of power system in your laptop and test it in the most extreme conditions.

Main features: - execution of quick testing to show battery ability during time of discharge by 4-6% - full testing of laptop power system with displaying of a graph of discharge - the ability to run calculating process to make a full load of each processor core - simulation of a load on the disk subsystem, including reading and writing data - calculation of the final mark to compare laptops or batteries - making of a report for use or research later

Author and developer